AMY PALOMINO DATA ANALYST

+447969 313686 | amy.pal@outlook.com | www.linkedin.com/in/amy-palomino | https://amypal.github.io

SUMMARY

A curious and creative individual with a keen eye for detail and forensic approach to solving a problem. Several years of retail management experience has instilled a strong understanding of how critical data is to make meaningful decisions. Developed a wide range of experiences, from people management and training, to reading a P&L sheet and using data to budget labour, plan and execute sales forecasts and analyse contribution.

ANALYTICAL SKILLS

Excel | Power BI & DAX | Tableau | SQL | Relational Databases | Python | Statistical Analysis | Addressing data quality issues and outliers | Data Visualisation | Predictive Analysis | Critical Thinking | Problem Solving

SOFT SKILLS

People Management | Training | Developing others | Communication | Empathy | Curiosity | Storytelling

PROJECTS

Tableau & SQL – Provide key insights to inform the online rental launch strategy for Rockbuster, a film rental company using SQL

- o Queried relational database to determine customer lifetime value and recommendations for film library.
- o Presented a compelling story using Tableau to deliver findings
- o Project link https://public.tableau.com/app/profile/amy.palomino/viz/Ex3_10_16471992613500

Python & Excel – Inform the marketing strategy for an online grocery company Instacart through exploratory analysis

- O Using Jupyter notebooks and various Python libraries, explored consumer habits and trends, answering business questions such as "Is there a connection between age & family status in terms of ordering habits?"
- o Presented finding and recommendations in an excel report
- o Project link https://github.com/amypal/CF_Python_InstaCart_Analysis

Python & Tableau – Exploring relationships between global natural disasters occurring between 1970 and 2021.

- o Regression, clustering and time-series analysis were used to explore the type and frequency of disaster, focusing on specific regions, looking at increasing magnitude and the number of people affected.
- o Insights presented in Tableau, to tell a compelling story around the impact and frequency of certain disaster types and rising global temperatures.
- o Project Link https://public.tableau.com/app/profile/amy.palomino/viz/GlobaloccuranceofNaturalDisastersbetween1970 and2021

EMPLOYMENT

Neal's Yard Dairy London

Reporting, BI Analysis & Inventory (Oct 20 – Present)

- o Created and continue to evolve Power BI reports for retail, providing metrics on sales, labour and wastage and customer and product insights to facilitate peak planning and manage costs
- o Developing W/S Power BI reports covering KPIs with drill throughs to customer and product insights
- o Established and developed forecasting sheets for Retail Managers, providing a decision-making tool to determine sales, cost and labour plans based on forecast departmental contribution
- o Implemented a new retail database across 4 sites within project budget
 - Devised a new discount structure, simplifying database
 - Developed user manuals and delivered training for all users
 - Integrated a retail stock management system, improving stock replenishment and efficiencies between departmental transfers

- o Maintaining the retail database to optimise data quality
- o Analysing inventory adjustments company-wide to better understand usage and wastage metrics departmentally as well as improve the inventory systems to better manage stock

Non-Resale Buying & Contracts (Jul 21- Aug 22)

- o Responsible for all service and utility contracts
 - Monitoring invoicing and scheduling contractors
 - Negotiating contracts to suit the needs of the company and manage costs associated
- o Overseeing the purchasing of non-resale stock
 - Mentoring the Non-Resale Purchasing Assistant, providing support and development within purchasing role
 - Planning for peak seasonal sales, ensuring there are no bottlenecks in supply and departmental needs are met. Developed a forecasting sheet to calculate packaging requirements based on order split
 - Analysed packaging scenarios and drove a cost saving initiative to reduce ecommerce packaging costs by
 10%

Retail Manager Oct 2014 - Sep 2020

- o Managed the largest retail site in Borough Market from 2018
 - Responsibilities included financial planning and reporting, people and stock management, H&S and Quality Assurance compliance
 - Built and shaped a successful team to achieve record breaking sales figures in December 2019, increasing a single days' take by 15%
- o Events and Markets Manager which included organising and leading national and international events
 - Successfully organised and led a team of 30 staff, to retail at the biennial Slow Food Cheese event in Bra,
 Italy, beating previous sales records in 2017, by 10%

Cheese Monger Jun 2011 – Sep 2014

- o Honed sales skills and craftsmanship required to do an exceptional job
 - Overhauled the shop replenishment system
 - Led Christmas Markets in Winchester, Oxford and Salisbury, demonstrating the ability to independently plan and execute, lead a team and deliver on sales targets.

EDUCATION

Data Analytics

Career Foundry November 2021 – July 2022

BA (Hons) Printed Textile Design

First Class Honours University for the Creative Arts 2006 - 2009

Art & Design Diploma in Foundation Studies

Distinction Exeter College 2005 - 2006